{
	"data":[
		{
			"question":"Who invented Java Programming?",
			"options" : ["Guido van Rossum","James Gosling","Dennis Ritchie","Bjarne Stroustrup"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: Java programming was developed by James Gosling at Sun Microsystems in 1995. James Gosling is well known as the father of Java."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which statement is true about Java?",
			"options" : [
			"Java is a sequence-dependent programming language",
			"Java is a code dependent programming language",
			"Java is a platform-dependent programming language",
			"Java is a platform independent programming language"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: Java is called 'Platform Independent Language' as it primarily works on the principle of 'compile once, run everywhere'."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
			"options" : ["JRE","JIT","JDK","JVM"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: JDK is a core component of Java Environment and provides all the tools, executables and binaries required to compile, debug and execute a Java Program."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
			"options" : ["Object-oriented","Use of pointers","Portable","Dynamic and Extensible"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: Pointers is not a Java feature. Java provides an efficient abstraction layer for developing without using a pointer in Java. Features of Java Programming are Portable, Architectural Neutral, Object-Oriented, Robust, Secure, Dynamic and Extensible, etc"
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java?",
			"options" : ["identifier & keyword","identifier","keyword","none of the mentioned"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: Keywords are specially reserved words that can not be used for naming a user defined variable, for example: class, int, for, etc."
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the extension of java code files?",
			"options" : [".js",".txt",".class",".java"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: Java files have .java extension."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
			"options" : ["MAVEN_HOME","CLASSPATH","JAVA","JAVA_HOME"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: JAVA_HOME is used to store a path to the java installation."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
			"options" : ["Polymorphism","Inheritance","Compilation","Encapsulation"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: There are 4 OOPS concepts in Java. Inheritance, Encapsulation, Polymorphism and Abstraction."
		},
		{
			"question":"What is not the use of \"this\" keyword in Java?",
			"options" : [
			"Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
			"Passing itself to the method of the same class",
			"Passing itself to another method",
			"Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
			],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: \"this\" is an important keyword in java. It helps to distinguish between local variable and variables passed in the method as parameters."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
			"options" : ["Multiple polymorphism","Compile time polymorphism","Multilevel polymorphism","Execution time polymorphism"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: There are two types of polymorphism in Java. Compile time polymorphism (overloading) and runtime polymorphism (overriding)."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of the following package is used for text formatting in Java programming language?",
			"options" : ["java.io","java.awt.text","java.awt","java.text"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: java.text allows formatting, searching and manipulating text."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of the following is not a segment of memory in java?",
			"options" : ["Code Segment","Register Segment","Stack Segment","Heap Segment"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: There are only 3 types of memory segment. Stack Segment, Heap Segment and Code Segment."
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the extension of compiled java classes?",
			"options" : [".txt",".js",".class",".java"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: The compiled java files have .class extension."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which exception is thrown when java is out of memory?",
			"options" : ["MemoryError","OutOfMemoryError","MemoryOutOfBoundsException","MemoryFullException"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: The Xms flag has no default value, and Xmx typically has a default value of 256MB. A common use for these flags is when you encounter a java.lang.OutOfMemoryError."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these are selection statements in Java?",
			"options" : ["break","continue","for()","if()"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: Continue and break are jump statements, and for is a looping statement."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these coding types is used for data type characters in Java?",
			"options" : ["ISO-LATIN-1","UNICODE","ASCII","None of the mentioned"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: Unicode defines fully international character set that can represent all the characters found in all human languages. Its range is from 0 to 65536."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these class is a superclass of every class in Java?",
			"options" : ["ArrayList class","Abstract class","Object class","String class"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: Object class is superclass of every class in Java."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which of these keywords are used for the block to be examined for exceptions?",
			"options" : ["check","throw","catch","try"],
			"answer":"d \nExplanation: try is used for the block that needs to checked for exception."
		},
		{
			"question":"Which one of the following is not an access modifier?",
			"options" : ["Protected","Void","Public","Private"],
			"answer":"b \nExplanation: Public, private, protected and default are the access modifiers."
		},
		{
			"question":"What is the numerical range of a char data type in Java?",
			"options" : ["0 to 256","-128 to 127","0 to 65535","0 to 32767"],
			"answer":"c \nExplanation: Char occupies 16-bit in memory, so it supports 216 i:e from 0 to 65535."
		}
	]
}